Hello and welcome to
Biodose Tools installation guide
To install Biodose Tools on your local system we
will follow the User Guide & Documentation website
Links to download R and RStudio are available
on the "Getting Biodose Tools" section
First we'll need to download R; we
will open the CRAN link on another tab
If we scroll down we will see
the link to download RStudio
To download R, click on "Download R for Windows"
To download RStudio, click on
"Download RStudio for Windows"
Once the downloads have finished, open your
Downloads folder and execute the R installer
Just follow the instructions and wait
until the installation is finished
It may take a couple of minutes
depending on your computer's speed
After R is installed, open the RStudio
installer on your Downloads folder
Again, just follow the instructions and
wait until the installation is finished
With this we have concluded the
installation of R and RStudio
and we are ready to install Biodose Tools
First of all, we will need to open RStudio
After the session has loaded
type install.packages("devtools") on the console
to be able install the developer version of Biodose Tools from GitHub
To install Biodose Tools type
devtools::install_github("biodosetools-team/biodosetools")
During the installation we will
be asked to update some packages;
we can simply reply 3 to update none
Now RStudio will install all dependencies
required to run Biodose Tools
Depending on your operating system and computer
speed this process will take a few more minutes
Once the installation is finished
you will see "DONE" on the console
Now we will run Biodose Tools
for the first time on RStudio
Once the session is open, you can type
biodosetools::run_app() and press Enter
On the home page we will see the "Source code",
"Documentation", and "Report issue" buttons
On the sidebar we can see the different
modules for each aberration assay
To exit Biodose Tools simply close the window
You can then close RStudio